<section id="birth_of_kurus">
	<title>Birth of Kurus</title>
	<para>
		In due course of time,
		<phrase>Ambika</phrase>
		gave
		birth to a blind boy,
		<phrase>Dhritarashtra</phrase>
		>, while

		her sister
		<phrase>Ambalika</phrase>
		bore an albino boy,
		<phrase>Pandu</phrase>
		.
	</para>

	<para>
		After Ambika started menstruating again, Satyavati asked her
		to mate Vyaas once more, but she could not because
		she still remembered his
		ugly face,
		his stinking body odor.
		Instead she sent one of her
		<emphasis>shudra</emphasis>
		chambermaids to Vyaas.
	</para>

	<para>
		The maid bore 
		<phrase>Bidur</phrase>
		.
	</para>


	<para>
		Vyaas was pleased with the beautiful maid and the way she cared for him. Afterward he
		told her: "O good-natured woman, you will no more be a serf. You will be mother
		of a pious and smart son".
	</para>


	<blockquote>

		<para>
			<phrase>Mandavya</phrase>
			was a silent monk who always held his hand straight above his head. Once some thieves
			stashed their loot in Mandavya's temple. The police came to the temple and questioned
			Mandavya. But Mandavya did not speak.

		</para>

		<para>

			Later when police caught the thieves, the
			police also arrested Mandavya as an accomplice and produced them to the royal court.
		</para>

		<para>

			The king sentenced all the accused to
			<emphasis>death-by-spear</emphasis>
			.
		</para>

		<para>

			Each culprit was placed on top of
			a spear until death, but Mandavya remained alive because of his meditative power.
		</para>

		<para>

			When the king realized that Mandavya was a monk and not a thief, he was brought
			down, but the spearhead stayed inside his body.
		</para>

		<para>

			After the unfortunate incidence,
			Mandavya roamed and spread his teachings. Because of his condition he
			became known as
			<phrase>Oni Mandavya</phrase>
			.
		</para>

		<para>

			Once he met
			<phrase>Dharma</phrase>
			– the god of Justice – and asked him: "Why did you punish me so harshly? What did
			I do wrong?"
		</para>

		<para>

			Dharma said: "You had inserted a blade of grass in a grasshopper’s
			anus when you were a kid. Your punishment is a result of that cruel act".
		</para>

		<para>

			"Dharma, you have
			punished me way out of proportion.
			Killing a
			<emphasis>brahmin</emphasis>
			is more critical than
			killing any other form of life. I curse you that someday you will be born as a lowly 
			<emphasis>shudra</emphasis>
			.
			Also I proclaim that any guilty act will be adjudged juvenile
			crime before the age of fourteen.
		</para>

		<para>

			It was on Oni Mandavya's curse, Dharma was born as Bidur
			of a
			<emphasis>shudra</emphasis>
			chambermaid.
		</para>
	</blockquote>
</section>