<section  id="death_of_pandu">
<title>Death of Pandu</title>
<para>
Pandu went on a campaign with army and return with
conquest. He donated conquered wealth to Visma, his tow mothers and Vidur. Then
he went for a hunt with his two wives.
  </para>
  
  <para>
Vyaas had foretold that Dhritarashtra would father hundred sons. 
However, his eife Gahdhari became pregnant
but she did not deliver in two years. 
She grew even more impatient and jealous when 
she came to know that
Kunti had given birth to Yudhisthira. 
</para>
  
  <para>
Gandhari aborted with DhritaRashtra's knowledge. 
A piece of meat as hard as iron
came out of her womb. 
</para>
  
  <para>
She was dumping the meat when Vyaas appeared and said: "My
prophecy will not fail. Soak this meat in cold water". 
</para>
  
  <para>
Gandhari soaked the meat and soon hundreds
of small finger-like spores grew out of the meat. She kept each spore in separate
pitcher submerged in butter. After a year, DuryoDhan was
born from one of the pitchers. 
  </para>
  
  <para>
DuryoDhan roared like a donkey as soon as he was born.
Also vultures, jackals and ravens cried and many other omens were observed. 
</para>
  
  <para>
DhritaRashtra was worried and  asked Vishma and Bidur:
"Yudhisthira is the eldest and heir to the throne, but after him, will my son
be the king?"
  </para>
  
  <para>
Noticing the omens, Bidur and Bramhins advised: "Your son will ruin this clan,
better to abandon him now." 
  </para>
  
  <para>
But  DhritaRashtra could not abandon his firstborn. Within another month, 
hundred other sons -- DuhShashan, DuhShah
etcetera and a daughter -- DuhShala were born.
</para>
  
  <para> 
A prostitute used to take care of DhritaRashtra during Gandhari's pregnency,
She too bore a son -- Yuyutsu.
</para>
  
  <para>
 One day, Pandu shot and killed a  deer while it was copulating. 
   </para>
   
   
   <para>
 
The wounded deer said: "Not even the worst criminal will kill a copulating deer!
I am saint Kimindam, I was in an intercourse with my wife in the
form of a deer. You did not know that I am a Bramhin, so you would not be guilty
of Bramhinicide. But I curse you: you too will die during intercourse."
  </para>
  
  <para>
Cursed Paudu wailed and said: "I would become a monk and an ascetic. I can not father
a child anymore due to the curse, I will stop being a family man". 
  </para>
  
    <para>
Kunti and Madri, his queens, said:"We are your lawful wives. We will follow you and 
curb our amorous desires for you".
    </para>
  
    <para>
  
Then Pandu and his wives donated their possessions to bramhins and went to the forest
to live an ascetic's life.
  </para>
  


</section>





