<section  xml:id="marriage_proposal">
<title>Marriage Proposal</title>
<para>
<phrase role="actor">Shantanu</phrase> returned to <phrase>Hastinapur</phrase> 
with his newfound son <phrase>Debabrata</phrase>. 
Soon he anointed Debabrata as prince. Everyone liked
 the new young prince. 
   </para>
   
   
<para>
 Four years later, On one evening, Shantanu was strolling in
 the bank of river <phrase>Yamuna</phrase> when an intriguing perfume drew him in.
    </para>
    
    

<para>
 
 The scent drew him deep inside the woods in front of a young ravishing beauty. 
 Shantanu
 asked the girl who she is. 
 The girl said: <quote>My name is <phrase role="actor">Satyavati</phrase>. My dad
 is the king of the fishermen. I row boats in Yamuna</quote>. 
      </para>
<para>
   
 Shantanu, smitten by Satyavati's beauty,
 visited her father <phrase  role="actor">Dass</phrase> in fishermen's grove 
 and asked him his
 daughter's hand for marriage. 
      </para>
<para>
   
 Dass said: <quote>O King, I am honored by your offer. But
 you must promise the throne to her yet-to-be-born son</quote>. 
       </para>
<para>
    
 Shantanu could not make such a promise on the spot. 
 He returned to the palace, his mind occupied by a charming
 young face of a fragrant beauty. 
      </para>
<para>

   <?dbhtml-include href="../../../script/hr.html"?>
   
 Debabrata noticed  pensive mood of his father for few weeks
 before asking: <quote>O mighty king, peace reigns all over the kingdom. The borders are
 safe and secure from the enemies. Yet, why are you so worried? You don't ride the
 horses in the morning, nor you go for the evening stroll, you look pale and lost
 weight. What is eating you up?</quote> 
      </para>
<para>
   
 Shantanu answered: <quote>Oh my dear son, you are the
 <emphasis>sole</emphasis> heir to Bharath clan. 
 You are a great warrior, I know. But human life is tenuous. 
 God forbid, something happens to you, the great 
 bloodline of Bharatha will cease. 
 You worth more than hundred sons to me and that is why I do
 not wish to marry again. 
 But the wise says that a single son is no better than
 no son at all. This is what makes me worry</quote>. 
       </para>
<para>
    
 Debabrata sensed something more than
 continuing legacy of royal bloodline is bothering his old man. 
 So he consulted his
 father's chief secretary: <quote>What's wrong with my father? 
 Why is he so pensive lately?</quote>
 The chief secretary revealed the real cause. 
      </para>
<para>

   <?dbhtml-include href="../../../script/hr.html"?>
   
 Debabrata immediately went to meet
 fisherman Dass with a group of senior statesmen. 
 He requested  Dass on behalf of his father for Satyavati's
 hand in marriage. 
      </para>
<para>
   
 Dass received Debabrata with due respect but reiterated: 
 <quote>O Prince, beloved of all, who would not be honored by such a proposal? My daughter,
 Satyavati is fit to be the queen of the great emperor Shantanu. 
 But <emphasis>you</emphasis>
 will be her future son's  step-brother. 
 Who could be happy to play second fiddle to a
 an all-rounder prince like you?</quote>
 </para>
   
 
 
 </section>