<section  xml:id="pledge_like_none">
<title>Pledge Like No Other</title>

<para>
Debabrata announced: <quote>Let me make a pledge. 
A pledge that no one had ever made. The
 son born of wedlock of <phrase>Satyavati</phrase> and 
 king <phrase>Shantanu</phrase>
 will become the future king of <phrase>Hastinapur</phrase>, not me</quote>. 
      </para>
<para>
   
 King Dass said:<quote>
 O great, gentle prince, you are the sole support of King Shantanu. Now you have
 become the savior of my daughter as well. You are so magnanimous that you deserve
 the right to give away the bride in this marriage. But as a father of the bride,
 I still have some concerns</quote>. 
      </para>
<para>
   
 Willy Dass continued: <quote>Everyone knows that you will
 never go back on your pledge. I too am not worried about that. 
 But it is your <emphasis>unborn</emphasis>
 son that I am afraid of</quote>. 
      </para>
<para>
   
 Debabrata said: <quote>I have already pledged to relinquish
 the throne. Let me make another pledge: 
 <emphasis>I will never father a child</emphasis>. From
 now, I will be a celibate for ever. 
 I will attain heaven, despite being childless</quote>.
   
    </para>
<para>
 
 King Dass and everyone was overwhelmed by Debabrata's pledge. Dass finally gave
 his consent for marriage.
      </para>

<?dbhtml-include href="../../../script/hr.html"?>

<para>

 The gods were impressed as well.  
 They rained flowers from  heaven. 
      </para>
      
      
<para>
 They renamed
 Debabrata as <phrase>Vishma</phrase> – 
 <emphasis>one who accomplish extremely difficult
 tasks</emphasis>. 
      </para>
<para>
   
 Having secured the consent of Dass, Vishma invited Satyavati to
 his chariot: "Mother, please get in. Let us go home". 
    
    </para>
    
    <?dbhtml-include href="../../../script/hr.html"?>
    
<para>
 
 They returned to Hastinapur
 and Vishma debriefed his father. 
 Everyone was full of praise of Debabrata, now
 Vishma, for his unprecedented pledge.
 </para>
 
 <para>
  <quote>He is truly Vishma. He has pledged what
 nobody did and perhaps ever will</quote>: they said. 
      </para>
      
      
<para>
   
 Shantanu – the happiest beneficiary of Vishma's
 pledge and elated with a new beautiful bride – blessed his son: 
  <quote>My sinless dear
 son, you will live as long as you wish. Death will not claim you, until you wish
 to die</quote>. 
      </para>
   
 
 
 </section>