<section  xml:id="surrogate_birth">
<title>Surrogate Birth</title>

<para>
<phrase>Satyavati</phrase>, despite losing her sons, consoled widowed daughter-in-laws.
 She commanded <phrase>Vishma</phrase>: "You have to bear the torch of 
 King <phrase>Shantanu</phrase>
 now. You know theology and are aware of the tradition of our clan. On my permission
 either you impregnate your sister-in-laws or take the throne yourself and marry.
 In any case, do not let your forefathers rot in hell". 
   </para>
   
   <para>
 Vishma said: "Mother, I can
 sacrifice everything on earth, heaven and hell. But I can not break my pledge. I
 have a plan to keep our bloodline going forward".
    </para>
   
   <para>
  Vishma told Satyavati ancient practice surrogate birth. 
 
   </para>
   
   
 <blockquote>
 
 <para>
 In olden days, when <phrase>YamadAgnya Parashuram</phrase> annihilated the 
 entire warrior clan, the women of the
 warriors got pregnant with the Vedist <emphasis>brahmins</emphasis>, because Veda dictates that
 son begot by a surrogate sperm belongs to the married couple.
   </para>
   
   <para>
 Once Saint <phrase>BrihashPati</phrase> approached 
 <phrase>Mamata</phrase>
 – his pregnant sister-in-law, wife of Saint <phrase>Utathya</phrase>. 
 But Mamata
 was not willing to sleep with BrihashPati. 
 BrihashPati attempted to rape her and tried to
 enter her by force. 
      </para>
   
   <para>
 The unborn baby in Mamata's womb stopped his uncle's entry with
 his small feet. Angry BrihashPati cursed the unborn baby: "You will be blind". 
      </para>
   
   <para>
 Utathya's son was born blind. He was named <phrase>DirghaAtma</phrase>. 
      </para>
   
   <para>
 DirghaAtma took to <emphasis>Bovinism</emphasis>
 – a cult that practiced mating anywhere anytime, like animals.
    </para>
   
   <para> 
 The other priests
 were enraged at DirghaAtma's bovinism. They exiled him and DirghaAtma's sons
 floated him on a raft at their mother's command. 
      </para>
   
   <para>
 King <phrase>Bali</phrase> found
 the floating raft and took DirghaAtma home. 
 The king wanted DirghaAtma to be the
 biological father of his children. 
      </para>
   
   <para>
 King asked her wife, <phrase>Sudeshna</phrase>,
 to sleep with Dirghatama. But Sudeshna did not like  blind Dirghatama and sent
 her maid instead. 
      </para>
   
   <para>
 The maid – a low-caste, <phrase>shudra</phrase> woman – bore eleven children
 who grew up to be priests. 
      </para>
   
   <para>
 King Bali, however, kept insisting his wife.  Finally Sudeshna
 herself went to Dirghatama. Dirghatama touched her skin and said: "You will bear
 five mighty sons: <phrase>Aanga</phrase>, <phrase>Banga</phrase>, 
 <phrase>Kalinga</phrase>,
 <phrase>Pundra</phrase> and <phrase>Suksha</phrase>. 
 Each will rule a region after their
 own name. 
    </para>
   
   <para>
 
 That is the way the Bali dynasty was originated from DirghaAtma seed.
 </para>
 </blockquote>
 
 <para>
 Then Vishma said: "Mother, please employ a talented 
 <emphasis>brahmin</emphasis> to impregnate
 late BichitroBirya's wives". 
   </para>
 
 
 
 </section>