<section xml:id="vyaas-comes-to-rescue">
	<title>Vyaas Comes to Rescue</title>

	<para>
		<phrase>Satyavati</phrase>
		smiled at
		<phrase>Vishma</phrase>
		's suggestion.
		She then revealed
		her own past.
	</para>

	<para>
		She had a baby before her marriage. <quote>His name was
		<phrase>Dwiypaayan</phrase>
		</quote>:
		she said.
	</para>

	<para>
		<quote>He is a great scholar, a great saint, I hear</quote>: 
		she continued about her
		son: <quote>They titled him
		<phrase>Vyaas</phrase>
		because he had classified
		the Vedas into four categories.
		He is dark. Hence his other name is
		<phrase>Krishna</phrase>.
	He lives with his father
		<phrase>Parashar</phrase>.

		But he told me that he will
		always be there for me</quote>.
	</para>

	<para>

		<quote>Vishma, on our request,
		<phrase>Krishna Dwiypaayan Vyaas</phrase>
		will be ready to impregnate his sister-in-laws</quote>.

	</para>

	<para>

		Vishma agreed to Satyavati suggestion.

	</para>

	<para>



		As soon as Satyavati recalled him, Vyaas arrived in
		<phrase>HastinaPur</phrase>
		.
		Satyavati embraced her son, soaked him with milk from her breast and cried.
	</para>

	<para>

		Vyaas
		said: <quote>Your wish is my command, Mama. 
		Please tell me what do you wish?</quote>
	</para>

	<para>

		After listening to Satyavati's
		request, Vyaas said: <quote>I will carry it out only because of you. 
		Let the princesses
		be pure following the practices I suggest. 
		It will take an year. Then they may
		sleep with me</quote>.

	</para>

	<para>

		Satyavati told her son: <quote><emphasis>One full year</emphasis>?
		That will not do. It does not rain in a land that has no ruler. 
		The gods are not
		pleased with a land without a king. So no! we can not wait for an year.
		Make the princesses pregnant
		as soon as possible. Vishma will take care of the babies</quote>.

	</para>

	<para>
		Vyaas
		told his mother <quote>I am dark and ugly. My body stinks. 
		My rags are filthy. If it has to
		be done immediately, the princesses must endure all that</quote>.
	</para>

	<para>
		Satyavati had to cajole
		the princesses to meet with Vyaas.
	</para>

	<para>
		<phrase>Ambika</phrase>
		entered the bed chamber and while waiting
		for Vyaas, she fantasized Vishma and other mighty warriors. 
	</para>
	
	<para>
		After a while, Vyaas
		entered the bed chamber. 
		She was scared looking at Vyaas – his darkness, his burning
		eyes and long gray-black hairs in deep knots heaped on a serpentine pile over his
		head. She closed her eyes in fear...
	</para>

	<para>
		After Vyaas came out of the bed chamber finishing
		his duty, Satyavati asked him: "Will the child be worthy of a king?"
	</para>

	<para>

		Vyaas said:
		"He will be strong as hundred elephants, learned and intelligent and he will father
		hundred sons. But... he will be blind. It's because of his mother".
	</para>

	<para>


		Satyavati was not happy. She said: "A blind man is not fit to be
		the emperor of Kuru clan. You must give them another son".
	</para>

	<para>

		<phrase>Ambalika</phrase>
		– the other princess – entered the bed chamber next.
		But she tuned pale once she saw Vyaas.

		Later, Vyaas told Satyavati:
		"This son will be powerful, charismatic and father five sons. But... he will be an
		albino. It's because of his mother".
	</para>



</section>